<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bioinformatics | Microbial Infections and Immunology</title>
    <link>https://lbmii.github.io/category/bioinformatics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lbmii.github.io/category/bioinformatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Bioinformatics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lbmii.github.io/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/category/bioinformatics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tool for mapping short sequences to the genome</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/softwares/seqmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/softwares/seqmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a tool for mapping large amount of oligonucleotide to the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a tool for mapping large amount of short sequences to the genome. It is designed for finding all the places in a reference genome where each sequence may come from. This task is essential to the analysis of data from ultra high-throughput sequencing machines. With a carefully designed index-filtering algorithm and an efficient implementation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can map tens of millions of short sequences to a genome of several billions of nucleotides. Multiple substitutions and insertions/deletions of the nucleotide bases in the sequences can be tolerated and therefore detected. &lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; supports FASTA input format and various output formats, and provides command line options for tuning almost every aspect of the mapping process. A typical mapping can be done in a few hours on a desktop PC. Parallel use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on a cluster is also very straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-download  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jhui2014.github.io/seqmap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download SeqMap&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from official website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-download  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Research Article&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/24/20/2395/258850&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18697769/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PubMed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?linkname=pubmed_pubmed&amp;amp;from_uid=18697769&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see all similiar articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on PubMed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?linkname=pubmed_pubmed_citedin&amp;amp;from_uid=18697769&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;see all &amp;ldquo;Cited by&amp;rdquo; articles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on PubMed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/softwares/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Softwares &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web resources for functional studies of circular RNAs</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/circdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/circdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.circbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, you can explore public circRNA datasets and download the custom python scripts needed to discover circRNAs in your own (ribominus) RNA-seq data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.circbank.cn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circbank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for human circRNAs, where a novel naming system of circRNAs based on the host genes of circRNAs was implemented. In addition to the new naming system, circbank collected other five features of circRNAs including the miRNA binding site, conservation of circRNAs, m6A modification of circRNAs, mutation of circRNAs and protein-coding potential of circRNAs. &lt;a href=&#34;www.circbank.cn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circbank&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is publicly available and allows users to query, browse and download circRNAs with all six features we provided, based on different search criteria. The database may serve as a resource to facilitate the research of function and regulation of circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starbase.sysu.edu.cn/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCORI (The Encyclopedia of RNA Interactomes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an openly licensed and state-of-the-art platform to decode the cellular interaction networks among thousands of RNA binding proteins (RBPs) and various RNAs. We have identified millions of RBP-RNA and RNA-RNA interactions through analyzing thousands of CLIP-seq and various high-throughput sequencing data by developing new software and tools, and studied their functions and mechanisms in human diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reprod.njmu.edu.cn/cgi-bin/circrnadb/circRNADb.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIRCpedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an updated comprehensive database containing circRNA annotations from over 180 RNA-seq datasets across six different species. This atlas allows users to search, browse and download circRNAs with expression characteristics/features in various cell types/tissues, including disease samples. In addition, the updated database incorporates conservation analysis of circRNAs between humans and mice. Finally, the web interface also contains computational tools for the comparison of circRNA expression between samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reprod.njmu.edu.cn/cgi-bin/circrnadb/circRNADb.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADb&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database of circular RNA molecules in humans. It is freely available for non-commercial use. The latest version of this circRNA database contains 32,914 annotated exonic circRNAs, and can be a valuable resource for large-scale studies of circRNA, especially in humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are a novel class of RNAs with important biological implications. Currently, a huge number of circRNAs was already identified from high-throughput RNA-seq data sets. However, functional annotation and prioritization of these circRNAs for further expreimental validation as well as functional investigation is the bottleneck step for current circRNA studies. Now, we developed a new resource database and web tool named &lt;a href=&#34;http://circatlas.biols.ac.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circAtlas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that integrated over one millions of circRNAs across 6 species (human, macaca, mouse, rat, pig, chicken) and a variety of tissues. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://circatlas.biols.ac.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circAtlas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can fill this gap by integrating the most comprehensive circRNAs and their expression and functional profiles in vertebrates, which provides a foundation for circRNA studies and serves as a powerful starting point to investigate their biological significance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bis.zju.edu.cn/CircFunBase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircFunBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web-accessible database that aims to provide a high-quality functional circRNA resource including experimentally validated and computationally predicted functions. The current version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bis.zju.edu.cn/CircFunBase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircFunBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documents more than 7000 manually curated functional circRNA entries, mainly including Homo sapiens, Mus musculus, etc. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bis.zju.edu.cn/CircFunBase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircFunBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides visualized circRNA-miRNA interaction networks. In addition, a genome browser is provided to present the genome context of circRNAs. As a biological information platform for circRNAs, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bis.zju.edu.cn/CircFunBase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircFunBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will contribute for circRNA studies and bridge the gap between circRNAs and their functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-throughput genomic technologies like ChIP-seq and RNA-seq become more and more mature and inexpensive. A large number of circular RNAs (circRNAs) from back-spliced exons have been identified in various cell lines and across different species. However, transcriptional regulatory function of abundant circRNAs is unclear, so building a database of transcriptional regulatory information of circRNA is necessary. Here, based on ChIP-seq peaks of transcription factors binding sites (TFBSs) of each cell lines from ENCODE and all annotated human circRNAs from circBase, we developed a data source titled “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.licpathway.net/TRCirc/view/index&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRCirc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”, where enriched regions of TFBSs (peaks) from ChIP-seq experiments crossed with the regulatory region of circRNAs by their genomic coordinates, if a TFBS is located within the regulatory region of a certain circRNA, they form a TF and circRNA regulatory relationship (TF-circRNA). Moreover, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.licpathway.net/TRCirc/view/index&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRCirc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provided other correlation information, such as methylation level, H3K27ac signals, super-enhancers and expression of circRNAs. The current release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.licpathway.net/TRCirc/view/index&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRCirc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; incorporates 92375 circRNAs and 161 TFs in more than 100 cell types, involving the 690 uniform TFBS, 36 H3K27ac, 54 RNA-seq and 61 450k data sets. Users can search and browse TFBSs of circRNAs and other correlation information for particular TFs, cell lines or circRNAs of interest. Our tool also capacitates researchers to easily download TF-circRNA interactions for four classes regulatory region and other correlation information. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.licpathway.net/TRCirc/view/index&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TRCirc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is contributing to discovering transcription regulation mechanism of circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://circinteractome.nia.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircInteractome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts the miRNAs which can potentially target the circRNAs using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Targetscan&lt;/a&gt; prediction tool. This computational tool enables the prediction and mapping of binding sites for RBPs and miRNAs on reported circRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of CircInteractome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches circRNAs name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches the genomic position and best-matching transcripts of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrieves genomic and mature circRNA sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searches RBPs binding to a circRNA and to sequences upstream/downstream of the circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies RBPs binding to the circRNA junctions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifies miRNAs targeting a circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs divergent primers for circRNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designs siRNAs Specific to circRNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgga.org.cn:9091/circRNADisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a manually curated database of experimentally supported circRNA and disease associations. This database serves as an immeasurable source of knowledge for understanding the roles of circRNAs in human diseases. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgga.org.cn:9091/circRNADisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 includes detailed information on a circRNA-disease association, including circRNA (circBase ID, name, and/or synonyms) and disease name, the circRNA expression pattern (eg. up-regulated or down-regulated), experimental techniques (eg. qRT-PCR, microarray, and/or sequencing), circRNA partners (eg. interacting microRNA and/or genes), a brief functional and expression description about circRNA, literature references and other annotation information. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgga.org.cn:9091/circRNADisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 database provides a user-friendly, open access interface for an easy browse and search of each entry by circRNA, disease or host gene. Moreover, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgga.org.cn:9091/circRNADisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides useful links to other databases, including circRNAs in circBase, host gene in GeneCards. &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgga.org.cn:9091/circRNADisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;circRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also provides the hyper link to NCBI PubMed database together with an official PubMed ID and complete citation are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gb.whu.edu.cn/CSCD/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CSCD (Cancer-specific circRNAs database)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database developed for cancer-specific circRNAs. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gb.whu.edu.cn/CSCD/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CSCD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; collected available RNA sequencing (total RNA with rRNA depleted or polyA- enriched) datasets from 87 cancer cell line samples. We performed an integrated analysis by using 4 popular algorithms: CIRI, find_circ, circRNA_finder and circexplorer. We then collected circRNAs identified in only cancer samples but not any normal samples. Currently there are 272,152 cancer-specific circRNAs deposited in &lt;a href=&#34;http://gb.whu.edu.cn/CSCD/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CSCD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CircRNA is a new group of RNA which is generated from circularization of DNA. CircRNA has been established to be tissue-specific. &lt;a href=&#34;http://gb.whu.edu.cn/TSCD/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tissue-specific circRNA database (TSCD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is constructed to provide a global view of tissue-specific circRNA in main tissues of human and mouse and is able to contribute to identify new markers for organogenesis and development disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bio-inf.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircPrimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a user-friendly tool exploring circRNAs without any special skill required of the users. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bio-inf.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircPrimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows users to search, annotate and visualize circRNAs, and help users to design primers for circRNAs and check specificity of circRNA Primers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bio-inf.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CircPrimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; can show conserved circRNAs, and predict open reading frames (ORFs), internal ribosomal entry sites (IRESs) and m6A sites. It provides both a graphical and command-line interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases make long non-coding RNAs closer</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/lncrna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/lncrna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 17 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(human, mouse, cow, rat, chicken, fruitfly, zebrafish, celegans, yeast, Arabidopsis, chimpanzee, gorilla, orangutan, rhesus macaque, opossum platypus and pig). The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. We searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words ‘ncrna’, ‘noncoding’, ‘non-coding’,‘no code’, ‘non-code’, ‘lncrna’ or ‘lincrna. We retrieved the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html%29&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicresources.jcbose.ac.in/zhumur/lncrbase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) in Human and Mouse. With a total of 216562 lncRNA transcript entries,the database hosts information on basic lncRNA transcript features, with additional details on genomic location, overlapping small noncoding RNAs, associated Repeat Elements, associated imprinted genes, and lncRNA promoter information. Users can also search for microarray probes mapped to specific lncRNAs and associated disease information as well as search for lncRNA expression in a wide range of tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a public database for long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) sequence and annotation. The current release contains 127,802 transcripts and 56,946 genes. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offers 2,482 manually curated lncRNA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of human lncRNA expression profiles derived from re-annotation of public microarray expression data from over 57,000 samples spanning diverse cancers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enables the users to rapidly and intuitively explore differentially expressed lncRNAs of interest (annotated lncRNAs or any user-defined ones) in the context of different types of experiments. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a powerful platform for querying associations between lncRNA expression and cancer prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rna-society.org/rnalocate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RNALocate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a resource for efficient manipulation, browsing and analysis of RNA subcellular localization. The second version of RNALocate documents more than 210,000 RNA-associated subcellular localization entries with experimental evidence, involving more than 110,000 RNAs with 171 subcellular localizations in 104 species. It will be of help in elucidating the entirety of RNA-associated subcellular localization, and developing new prediction methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genome.igib.res.in/lncRNome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lncRNome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive searchable biologically oriented knowledgebase for long noncoding RNAs in Humans. The resource hosts information on over 17000 long noncoding RNAs in Human. The resource provides information on the types , chromosomal locations, description on the biological functions and disease associations of long noncoding RNAs. In addition, it provides access to datasets on protein-lncRNA interactions and genomic variations in lncRNA loci. The resource also provides a browsable interface for the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annolnc.gao-lab.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnnoLnc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web server to provide on-the-fly analysis for novel human or mouse lncRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are an important category of non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) which range from 200 nucleotides to multiple kilobases in length, with little or no protein-coding capacity. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are widely expressed in diverse eukaryotic species and are characterized by covalently closed RNA loops through backsplicing events. Increasing evidence has highlighted the critical roles of lncRNAs and circRNAs in plenty of diseases development and progression. Here, we have updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to version 2.0 by integrating comprehensive experimentally supported and predicted ncRNA-disease associations curated from manual literatures and other resources. The new developments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 include (I) over 40-fold ncRNA-disease associations enhancement compare to the previous version; (II) integrating experimentally supported circRNA-disease associations; (III) providing regulatory relationship among ncRNA, mRNA and miRNA; (IV) mapping disease name to the Disease Ontology and Medical Subject Headings (MeSH); (V) providing a confidence score for each ncRNA-disease association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaemons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts online services and databases developed by team of Dr Zhu and Dr Zhang at Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China. And has have integrated LongTarget into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/LongMan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LongMan&lt;/a&gt; to implement a seamless pipeline to implement this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCediting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Transcription Regulation Database (GTRD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains uniformly annotated and processed NGS data related to gene transcription regulation: ChIP-seq, ChIP-exo, DNase-seq, MNase-seq, ATAC-seq and RNA-seq. With the latest release, the database has reached a new level of data integration. All cell types (cell lines and tissues) presented in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were arranged into a dictionary and linked with different ontologies (BRENDA, Cell Ontology, Uberon, Cellosaurus and Experimental Factor Ontology) and with related experiments in specialized databases on transcription regulation (FANTOM5, ENCODE and GTEx). The updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an integrated view of transcription regulation through a dedicated web interface with advanced browsing and search capabilities, an integrated genome browser, and table reports by cell types, transcription factors, and genes of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web tools to analyse your miRNAs</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/mirna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/mirna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Last updation : 26 Oct 2022
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a first, manually curated platform gathering at the present over 170 methods for the broadly-defined miRNA analysis. All tools in &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are classified in the four general and seven more detailed categories. In each of the aforementioned sections user can additionally filter available methods according to his research needs, capabilities and preferences. Beside basic summary seen at first glance, the user can get detailed information concerning each tool. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a web-based target prediction meta-server incorporating user-designated target prediction methods in the analysis of user-provided data. Results generated by described meta-server can be presented in basic and extended form, while user can can additionally filter them using Union, Intersection or Consensus method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is free, open-access service which will be systematically updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database is a searchable database of published miRNA sequences and annotation. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sequence database represents a predicted hairpin portion of a miRNA transcript (termed mir in the database), with information on the location and sequence of the mature miRNA sequence (termed miR). Both hairpin and mature sequences are available for searching and browsing, and entries can also be retrieved by name, keyword, references and annotation. All sequence and annotation data are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/html/diana/web/index.php?r=tarbasev8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DIANA-TarBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was initially released in 2006 and it was the first database aiming to catalogue published experimentally validated miRNA:gene interactions. And it is one part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; suites. Actually, &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; provides several powerful tools facilitating your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an online database for miRNA target prediction and functional annotations. All the targets in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were predicted by a bioinformatics tool, MirTarget, which was developed by analyzing thousands of miRNA-target interactions from high-throughput sequencing experiments. Common features associated with miRNA binding and target downregulation have been identified and used to predict miRNA targets with machine learning methods. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts predicted miRNA targets in five species: human, mouse, rat, dog and chicken. Users may also provide their own sequences for custom target prediction using the updated prediction algorithm. In addition, through combined computational analyses and literature mining, functionally active miRNAs in humans and mice were identified. These miRNAs, as well as associated functional annotations, are presented in the FuncMir Collection in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As a recent update, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents the expression profiles of hundreds of cell lines and the user may limit their search for miRNA targets that are expressed in a cell line of interest. To facilitate the prediction of miRNA functions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents a new web interface for integrative analysis of target prediction and Gene Ontology data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an improved version of the previous database (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The new version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stores predicted data obtained with a maschine learning algorithm including experimentally verified miRNA-target interactions. The focus lies on accuracy, simplicity, user-friendly design and mostly up to date informations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts biological targets of miRNAs by searching for the presence of conserved 8mer, 7mer, and 6mer sites that match the seed region of each miRNA. As options, predictions with only poorly conserved sites and predictions with nonconserved miRNAs are also provided. Also identified are sites with mismatches in the seed region that are compensated by conserved 3&amp;rsquo; pairing. In mammals, predictions are ranked based on the predicted efficacy of targeting as calculated using a biochemical model of miRNA-mediated repression, which was extended to all miRNA sequences using a convolutional neural network. As an option, predictions are also ranked on the basis of targeting efficacy estimated using cumulative weighted context++ scores of the sites. As another option, predictions are ranked by their probability of conserved targeting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScanHuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; considers matches to human 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs and their orthologs, as defined by &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://www.genome.ucsc.edu/%29&#34;&gt;UCSC whole-genome&lt;/a&gt; alignments. Conserved targeting has also been detected within open reading frames (ORFs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/transmir&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TransmiR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database for transcription factor (TF)-microRNA (miRNA) regulations, through which one can find regulatory relations between TFs and miRNAs. This website has been tested by using Chrome, Microsoft Edge and Firefox browsers. Microsoft IE may not work well. More interestings can be found at Cui Lab of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics and Systems Biology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pictar.mdc-berlin.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PicTar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm for the identification of microRNA targets. This searchable website provides details (3&amp;rsquo; UTR alignments with predicted sites, links to various public databases etc) regarding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in vertebrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in seven Drosophila species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA targets in three nematode species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;human microRNA targets that are not conserved but co-expressed (i.e. the microRNA and mRNA are expressed in the same tissue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dashr2.lisanwanglab.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DASHR (Database of small human non-coding RNAs)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database developed at the University of Pennsylvania with the most comprehensive expression and processing information to date on all major classes of human small non-coding RNA (sncRNA) genes and mature sncNA annotations, expression levels, sequence and RNA processing information across 185 human tissues, cell types, and cell lines. The content of the database derives from integrating annotation data with curation, annotation, and computational analysis of 802 small-RNA (smRNA-seq) deep sequencing datasets with over 22 billion reads from &amp;gt;60 independent studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive databases for biomedical research</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/dbbmr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/dbbmr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Last updation : 30 Oct 2022
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://db.cngb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;China National GeneBank DataBase (CNGBdb)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a uniﬁed platform built for biological big data sharing and application services to the research community. Based on the big data and cloud computing technologies, it provides data services such as archive, analysis, knowledge search, management authorization, and visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; advances science and health by providing access to biomedical and genomic information. Probably, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Entrez/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Entrez&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GEO&lt;/a&gt; are the most frequently used sub-databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is one part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NCBI&lt;/a&gt; and a public functional genomics data repository supporting MIAME-compliant data submissions. Array- and sequence-based data are accepted. Tools are provided to help users query and download experiments and curated gene expression profiles. With &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GEO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, users can also analyze published data to identify genes that are differentially expressed across experimental conditions with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/geo2r/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GEO2R&lt;/a&gt;, where codes and scripts are no longer needed any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/biostudies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BioStudies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database holds descriptions of biological studies, links to data from these studies in other databases at EMBL-EBI or outside, as well as data that do not fit in the structured archives at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;. The database accepts submissions via an online tool, or in a simple tab-delimited format. It also enables authors to submit supplementary information and link to it from the publication. As a part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/biostudies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;BioStudies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/biostudies/arrayexpress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ArrayExpress&lt;/a&gt;, the functional genomics collection, stores data from high-throughput functional genomics experiments, and provides data for reuse to the research community. In line with community guidelines, a study typically contains metadata such as detailed sample annotations, protocols, processed data and raw data. Raw sequence reads from high-throughput sequencing studies are brokered to the European Nucleotide Archive (ENA), and links are provided to download the sequence reads from ENA. Data can be submitted to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/biostudies/arrayexpress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ArrayExpress&lt;/a&gt; collection through its dedicated submission tool, Annotare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensembl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a genome browser for vertebrate genomes that supports research in comparative genomics, evolution, sequence variation and transcriptional regulation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensembl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; annotate genes, computes multiple alignments, predicts regulatory function and collects disease data. &lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensembl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tools include BLAST, BLAT, BioMart and the Variant Effect Predictor (VEP) for all supported species. &lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensembl&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/platforms/data/core-data-resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR Core Data Resources&lt;/a&gt;. You can click to see more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.genome.ucsc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The UCSC Genome Browser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based tool serving as a multi-powered microscope that allows researchers to view all 23 chromosomes of the human genome at any scale from a full chromosome down to an individual nucleotide. The browser integrates the work of countless scientists in laboratories worldwide, including work generated at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucsc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UCSC&lt;/a&gt;, in an interactive, graphical display. The Browser also affords access to the genomes of more than one hundred other organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GENCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project is to identify and classify all gene features in the human and mouse genomes with high accuracy based on biological evidence, and to release these annotations for the benefit of biomedical research and genome interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/organization/ccg/research/structural-genomics/tcga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a landmark cancer genomics program, molecularly characterized over 20,000 primary cancer and matched normal samples spanning 33 cancer types. This joint effort between NCI and the National Human Genome Research Institute began in 2006, bringing together researchers from diverse disciplines and multiple institutions. Usually, we prefer to access the Database via &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.gdc.cancer.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Genomic Data Commons Data Portal&lt;/a&gt;. Other similar databases may also helpful, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbioportal.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cBioPortal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gepia2.cancer-pku.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GEPIA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://xena.ucsc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;UCSC Xena&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gdac.broadinstitute.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Broad GDAC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encodeproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia of DNA Elements (ENCODE)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Consortium is an ongoing international collaboration of research groups funded by the National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI). The goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encodeproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is to build a comprehensive parts list of functional elements in the human genome, including elements that act at the protein and RNA levels, and regulatory elements that control cells and circumstances in which a gene is active. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encodeproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ENCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; investigators employ a variety of assays and methods to identify functional elements. The discovery and annotation of gene elements is accomplished primarily by sequencing a diverse range of RNA sources, comparative genomics, integrative bioinformatic methods, and human curation. Regulatory elements are typically investigated through DNA hypersensitivity assays, assays of DNA methylation, and immunoprecipitation (IP) of proteins that interact with DNA and RNA, i.e., modified histones, transcription factors, chromatin regulators, and RNA-binding proteins, followed by sequencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noncode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 39 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noncode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; including 16 animals and 23 plants. The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noncode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noncode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; searches &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words &lt;code&gt;ncrna&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;noncoding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-coding&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;no code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;non-code&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lncrna&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;lincrna&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noncode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; retrieves the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;catRAPID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm to estimate the binding propensity of protein-RNA pairs. By combining secondary structure, hydrogen bonding and van der Waals contributions, &lt;a href=&#34;http://s.tartaglialab.com/page/catrapid_group&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;catRAPID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts protein-RNA associations with great accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene annotation and analysis resources</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/bioinfo1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/bioinfo1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Last updation : 06 Nov 2022
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://geneontology.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Ontology (GO)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; knowledgebase is the world’s largest source of information on the functions of genes. This knowledge is both human-readable and machine-readable, and is a foundation for computational analysis of large-scale molecular biology and genetics experiments in biomedical research. The mission of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://geneontology.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Consortium is to develop a comprehensive, computational model of biological systems, ranging from the molecular to the organism level, across the multiplicity of species in the tree of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.genome.jp/kegg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database resource for understanding high-level functions and utilities of the biological system, such as the cell, the organism and the ecosystem, from molecular-level information, especially large-scale molecular datasets generated by genome sequencing and other high-throughput experimental technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reactome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;REACTOME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source, open access, manually curated and peer-reviewed pathway database. The goal is to provide intuitive bioinformatics tools for the visualization, interpretation and analysis of pathway knowledge to support basic and clinical research, genome analysis, modeling, systems biology and education. Founded in 2003, the Reactome project is led by Lincoln Stein of &lt;a href=&#34;https://oicr.on.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OICR&lt;/a&gt;, Peter D’Eustachio of &lt;a href=&#34;https://nyulangone.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NYULMC&lt;/a&gt;, Henning Hermjakob of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EMBL-EBI&lt;/a&gt;, and Guanming Wu of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ohsu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OHSU&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;REACTOME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/platforms/data/core-data-resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR Core Data Resources&lt;/a&gt;. You can click to see more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsea-msigdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a computational method that determines whether an a priori defined set of genes shows statistically significant, concordant differences between two biological states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://metascape.org/gp/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metascape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a rather unique protein-protein interaction (PPI) network analysis capability. In many gene list analysis resources, PPI analysis results in a rather massy hairball network. Besides stating such networks are statistically significant, there is not much biologists can say about such networks. To infer more biologically interpretable results, &lt;a href=&#34;https://metascape.org/gp/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metascape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; applies a mature complex identification algorithm called &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2105-4-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MCODE&lt;/a&gt; to automatically extract protein complexes embedded in such large network. Then taking advantage of &lt;a href=&#34;https://metascape.org/gp/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metascape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;’s functional enrichment analysis capability, it automatically assigns putative biological roles of each &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmcbioinformatics.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2105-4-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MCODE&lt;/a&gt; complex. Such analyses are very computational intensive and cannot be easily computed even by bioinformaticians. Regardless of its advanced PPI analysis algorithm, the results still heavily determined by the quality of its underlying PPI database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;atabase for &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;nnotation, &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;isualization and &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;ntegrated &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;iscovery (&lt;a href=&#34;https://david.ncifcrf.gov/home.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DAVID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) provides a comprehensive set of functional annotation tools for investigators to understand the biological meaning behind large lists of genes. These tools are powered by the comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://david.ncifcrf.gov/home.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DAVID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Knowledgebase built upon the &lt;a href=&#34;https://david.ncifcrf.gov/home.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DAVID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Gene concept which pulls together multiple sources of functional annotations. For any given gene list, &lt;a href=&#34;https://david.ncifcrf.gov/home.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DAVID&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tools are able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify enriched biological themes, particularly GO terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover enriched functional-related gene groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster redundant annotation terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize genes on BioCarta &amp;amp; KEGG pathway maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display related many-genes-to-many-terms on 2-D view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for other functionally related genes not in the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List interacting proteins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore gene names in batch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link gene-disease associations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight protein functional domains and motifs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirect to related literatures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert gene identifiers from one type to another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profiling samples from patients, tissues, and cells with genomics, transcriptomics, epigenomics, proteomics, and metabolomics ultimately produces lists of genes and proteins that need to be further analyzed and integrated in the context of known biology. &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Enrichr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enrichr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a gene set search engine that enables the querying of hundreds of thousands of annotated gene sets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Enrichr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enrichr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; uniquely integrates knowledge from many high-profile projects to provide synthesized information about mammalian genes and gene sets. The platform provides various methods to compute gene set enrichment, and the results are visualized in several interactive ways. This protocol provides a summary of the key features of &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Enrichr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enrichr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which include using &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Enrichr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enrichr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; programmatically and embedding an &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/Enrichr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enrichr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; button on any website. To learn more about the platform, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33780170/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to access the free articles on PubMed for protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cn.string-db.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;STRING&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/platforms/data/core-data-resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR Core Data Resources&lt;/a&gt;. You can click to see more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elixir-europe.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ELIXIR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.genecards.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeneCards&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a searchable, integrative database that provides comprehensive, user-friendly information on all annotated and predicted human genes. The knowledgebase automatically integrates gene-centric data from about 150 web sources, including genomic, transcriptomic, proteomic, genetic, clinical and functional information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;genemania.org&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeneMANIA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps you predict the function of your favourite genes and gene sets. &lt;a href=&#34;genemania.org&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeneMANIA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; finds other genes that are related to a set of input genes, using a very large set of functional association data. Association data include protein and genetic interactions, pathways, co-expression, co-localization and protein domain similarity. You can use &lt;a href=&#34;genemania.org&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GeneMANIA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to find new members of a pathway or complex, find additional genes you may have missed in your screen or find new genes with a specific function, such as protein kinases. Your question is defined by the set of genes you input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.funrich.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Functional Enrichment analysis tool (FunRich)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a stand-alone software tool used mainly for functional enrichment and interaction network analysis of genes and proteins. Besides, the results of the analysis can be depicted graphically in the form of Venn, Bar, Column, Pie and Doughnut charts. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.funrich.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;FunRich&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; tool is designed to handle variety of gene/protein data sets irrespective of the organism. Users can not only search against default background database, but can also load customized database against which functional enrichment analysis can be carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cibersortx.stanford.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CIBERSORTx&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an analytical tool from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://med.stanford.edu/ash_alizadeh.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Alizadeh Lab&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://anlab.stanford.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Newman Lab&lt;/a&gt; to impute gene expression profiles and provide an estimation of the abundances of member cell types in a mixed cell population, using gene expression data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/archs4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARCHS4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides access to gene counts from HiSeq 2000, HiSeq 2500 and NextSeq 500 platforms for human and mouse experiments from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GEO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SRA&lt;/a&gt;. The website enables downloading of the data in H5 format for programmatic access as well as a 3-dimensional view of the sample and gene spaces. Search features allow browsing of the data by meta data annotation, ability to submit your own up and down gene sets, and explore matching samples enriched for annotated gene sets. Selected sample sets can be downloaded into a tab separated text file through auto-generated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; scripts for further analysis. Reads are aligned with Kallisto using a custom cloud computing platform. The artice about &lt;a href=&#34;https://maayanlab.cloud/archs4/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;ARCHS4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-018-03751-6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/a&gt; and can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29636450/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lisanwanglab.org/SPAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; integrates significantly improved mapping, segmentation, annotation, and RNA processing information for both sncRNA genes and mature sncRNA products. The improved mapping by &lt;a href=&#34;https://lisanwanglab.org/SPAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides significantly more data for downstream analysis (on average, over 28% more reads per library). &lt;a href=&#34;https://lisanwanglab.org/SPAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; segmentation is not only signficantly more accurate, but also is order-of-magnitude faster (60x speed-up on average) by utilizing novel segmentation algorithms. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lisanwanglab.org/SPAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has been used to process over 800 smRNA high-throughput sequencing (smRNA-seq) datasets from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GEO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SRA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.encodeproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ENCODE&lt;/a&gt; with over 20 billion reads. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lisanwanglab.org/SPAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; results are integrated into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://lisanwanglab.org/DASHR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;database of small human non-coding RNAs (DASHR)&lt;/a&gt; described in NAR 2016 Database issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss bioinformatics resource portal</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/expasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/expasy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the bioinformatics resource portal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Swiss Institute of Bioinformatics (SIB)&lt;/a&gt;. It is an extensible and integrative portal which provides access to over 160 databases and software tools, developed by SIB Groups and supporting a range of life science and clinical research domains, from genomics, proteomics and structural biology, to evolution and phylogeny, systems biology and medical chemistry. Thanks to a user-friendly search engine, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; allows users to seamlessly 1) query in parallel a subset of SIB databases through a single search, and to 2) surface related information and knowledge from the complete set of &amp;gt;160 resources on the portal. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides information that is automatically aligned with the most recent release of each resources, thereby ensuring up-to-date information. The terms used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.expasy.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expasy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article/29/10/1325/255660&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EDAM comprehensive ontology&lt;/a&gt;, which was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. The article about can also be accessed and downloaded on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23479348/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/expasy_hu49c47b7a40f3272e42c69cf438dfda89_165234_442c0f35ce294afae1878b67d4952eab.webp 400w,
               /media/expasy_hu49c47b7a40f3272e42c69cf438dfda89_165234_41a8fd258ccfd9db20ff636c48a1eda7.webp 760w,
               /media/expasy_hu49c47b7a40f3272e42c69cf438dfda89_165234_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/media/expasy_hu49c47b7a40f3272e42c69cf438dfda89_165234_442c0f35ce294afae1878b67d4952eab.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;506&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
