<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microRNAs | Microbial Infections and Immunology</title>
    <link>https://lbmii.github.io/tag/micrornas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lbmii.github.io/tag/micrornas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>microRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lbmii.github.io/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>microRNAs</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/tag/micrornas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web tools to analyse your miRNAs</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/mirna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/mirna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Last updation : 26 Oct 2022
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a first, manually curated platform gathering at the present over 170 methods for the broadly-defined miRNA analysis. All tools in &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are classified in the four general and seven more detailed categories. In each of the aforementioned sections user can additionally filter available methods according to his research needs, capabilities and preferences. Beside basic summary seen at first glance, the user can get detailed information concerning each tool. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a web-based target prediction meta-server incorporating user-designated target prediction methods in the analysis of user-provided data. Results generated by described meta-server can be presented in basic and extended form, while user can can additionally filter them using Union, Intersection or Consensus method. &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools4mirs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tools4miRs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is free, open-access service which will be systematically updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database is a searchable database of published miRNA sequences and annotation. Each entry in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Sequence database represents a predicted hairpin portion of a miRNA transcript (termed mir in the database), with information on the location and sequence of the mature miRNA sequence (termed miR). Both hairpin and mature sequences are available for searching and browsing, and entries can also be retrieved by name, keyword, references and annotation. All sequence and annotation data are also available for download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dianalab.e-ce.uth.gr/html/diana/web/index.php?r=tarbasev8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DIANA-TarBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was initially released in 2006 and it was the first database aiming to catalogue published experimentally validated miRNA:gene interactions. And it is one part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; suites. Actually, &lt;a href=&#34;http://diana.imis.athena-innovation.gr/DianaTools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DIANA&lt;/a&gt; provides several powerful tools facilitating your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an online database for miRNA target prediction and functional annotations. All the targets in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were predicted by a bioinformatics tool, MirTarget, which was developed by analyzing thousands of miRNA-target interactions from high-throughput sequencing experiments. Common features associated with miRNA binding and target downregulation have been identified and used to predict miRNA targets with machine learning methods. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts predicted miRNA targets in five species: human, mouse, rat, dog and chicken. Users may also provide their own sequences for custom target prediction using the updated prediction algorithm. In addition, through combined computational analyses and literature mining, functionally active miRNAs in humans and mice were identified. These miRNAs, as well as associated functional annotations, are presented in the FuncMir Collection in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As a recent update, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents the expression profiles of hundreds of cell lines and the user may limit their search for miRNA targets that are expressed in a cell line of interest. To facilitate the prediction of miRNA functions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirdb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRDB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; presents a new web interface for integrative analysis of target prediction and Gene Ontology data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an improved version of the previous database (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The new version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mirwalk.umm.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;miRWalk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stores predicted data obtained with a maschine learning algorithm including experimentally verified miRNA-target interactions. The focus lies on accuracy, simplicity, user-friendly design and mostly up to date informations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; predicts biological targets of miRNAs by searching for the presence of conserved 8mer, 7mer, and 6mer sites that match the seed region of each miRNA. As options, predictions with only poorly conserved sites and predictions with nonconserved miRNAs are also provided. Also identified are sites with mismatches in the seed region that are compensated by conserved 3&amp;rsquo; pairing. In mammals, predictions are ranked based on the predicted efficacy of targeting as calculated using a biochemical model of miRNA-mediated repression, which was extended to all miRNA sequences using a convolutional neural network. As an option, predictions are also ranked on the basis of targeting efficacy estimated using cumulative weighted context++ scores of the sites. As another option, predictions are ranked by their probability of conserved targeting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.targetscan.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TargetScanHuman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; considers matches to human 3&amp;rsquo; UTRs and their orthologs, as defined by &lt;a href=&#34;%28http://www.genome.ucsc.edu/%29&#34;&gt;UCSC whole-genome&lt;/a&gt; alignments. Conserved targeting has also been detected within open reading frames (ORFs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/transmir&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TransmiR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database for transcription factor (TF)-microRNA (miRNA) regulations, through which one can find regulatory relations between TFs and miRNAs. This website has been tested by using Chrome, Microsoft Edge and Firefox browsers. Microsoft IE may not work well. More interestings can be found at Cui Lab of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuilab.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioinformatics and Systems Biology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pictar.mdc-berlin.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PicTar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an algorithm for the identification of microRNA targets. This searchable website provides details (3&amp;rsquo; UTR alignments with predicted sites, links to various public databases etc) regarding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in vertebrates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA target predictions in seven Drosophila species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microRNA targets in three nematode species&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;human microRNA targets that are not conserved but co-expressed (i.e. the microRNA and mRNA are expressed in the same tissue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dashr2.lisanwanglab.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;DASHR (Database of small human non-coding RNAs)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database developed at the University of Pennsylvania with the most comprehensive expression and processing information to date on all major classes of human small non-coding RNA (sncRNA) genes and mature sncNA annotations, expression levels, sequence and RNA processing information across 185 human tissues, cell types, and cell lines. The content of the database derives from integrating annotation data with curation, annotation, and computational analysis of 802 small-RNA (smRNA-seq) deep sequencing datasets with over 22 billion reads from &amp;gt;60 independent studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
