<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lncRNAs | Microbial Infections and Immunology</title>
    <link>https://lbmii.github.io/tag/lncrnas/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lbmii.github.io/tag/lncrnas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>lncRNAs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lbmii.github.io/media/icon_hu1efa9af2edf414d45fb59503b457ea16_13437_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>lncRNAs</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/tag/lncrnas/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases make long non-coding RNAs closer</title>
      <link>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/lncrna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lbmii.github.io/resources/database/lncrna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an integrated knowledge database dedicated to non-coding RNAs (excluding tRNAs and rRNAs). Now, there are 17 species in &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(human, mouse, cow, rat, chicken, fruitfly, zebrafish, celegans, yeast, Arabidopsis, chimpanzee, gorilla, orangutan, rhesus macaque, opossum platypus and pig). The source of &lt;a href=&#34;http://v5.noncode.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NONCODE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; includes literature and other public databases. We searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt; using key words ‘ncrna’, ‘noncoding’, ‘non-coding’,‘no code’, ‘non-code’, ‘lncrna’ or ‘lincrna. We retrieved the new identified lncRNAs and their annotation from the Supplementary Material or web site of these articles. Together with the newest data from &lt;a href=&#34;%28https://asia.ensembl.org/index.html%29&#34;&gt;Ensembl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/refseq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RefSeq&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lncrnadb.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lncRNAdb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gencodegenes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GENCODE&lt;/a&gt; were processed through a standard pipeline for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicresources.jcbose.ac.in/zhumur/lncrbase/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive database for long noncoding RNA (lncRNA) in Human and Mouse. With a total of 216562 lncRNA transcript entries,the database hosts information on basic lncRNA transcript features, with additional details on genomic location, overlapping small noncoding RNAs, associated Repeat Elements, associated imprinted genes, and lncRNA promoter information. Users can also search for microarray probes mapped to specific lncRNAs and associated disease information as well as search for lncRNA expression in a wide range of tissues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a public database for long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) sequence and annotation. The current release contains 127,802 transcripts and 56,946 genes. Currently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncipedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; offers 2,482 manually curated lncRNA articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a catalog of human lncRNA expression profiles derived from re-annotation of public microarray expression data from over 57,000 samples spanning diverse cancers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enables the users to rapidly and intuitively explore differentially expressed lncRNAs of interest (annotated lncRNAs or any user-defined ones) in the context of different types of experiments. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lncar.renlab.org/#welcome&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lnCAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is also a powerful platform for querying associations between lncRNA expression and cancer prognosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are emerging as key factors in the regulation of various cellular processes and diseases. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/lncRNASNP#!/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNASNP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a database providing comprehensive resources of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in human/mouse lncRNAs. It contains SNPs in lncRNAs, SNP effects on lncRNA structure, mutation in lncRNAs and lncRNA:miRNA binding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs) play an important role in modulating gene expression or participating in some essential epigenetic regulation processes, including chromatin modification or DNA methylation. DNA methylation is a fundamental feature of epigenomes that can affect the expression of protein-coding or non-coding transcripts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bio-bigdata.hrbmu.edu.cn/Lnc2Meth/index.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lnc2Meth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a comprehensive resource and web tool for clarifying the regulatory relationships between human lncRNAs and associated DNA methylation in diverse diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rna-society.org/rnalocate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;RNALocate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aims to provide a resource for efficient manipulation, browsing and analysis of RNA subcellular localization. The second version of RNALocate documents more than 210,000 RNA-associated subcellular localization entries with experimental evidence, involving more than 110,000 RNAs with 171 subcellular localizations in 104 species. It will be of help in elucidating the entirety of RNA-associated subcellular localization, and developing new prediction methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of extracellular vesicles (EVs) long RNAs (exLRs) derived from RNA-seq data analyses in different human body fluids. The exLRs contain messenger RNA (mRNA), long non-coding RNA (lncRNA), and circular RNA (circRNA). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exorbase.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;exoRBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 provides the comprehensive annotation and expression landscapes of exLRs. It will facilitate the identification of novel exLR signatures from human body fluids and will help discover new circulating biomarkers for the improvement of tumor diagnosis and therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genome.igib.res.in/lncRNome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lncRNome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive searchable biologically oriented knowledgebase for long noncoding RNAs in Humans. The resource hosts information on over 17000 long noncoding RNAs in Human. The resource provides information on the types , chromosomal locations, description on the biological functions and disease associations of long noncoding RNAs. In addition, it provides access to datasets on protein-lncRNA interactions and genomic variations in lncRNA loci. The resource also provides a browsable interface for the datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://annolnc.gao-lab.org/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AnnoLnc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a web server to provide on-the-fly analysis for novel human or mouse lncRNAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) are an important category of non-coding RNAs (ncRNAs) which range from 200 nucleotides to multiple kilobases in length, with little or no protein-coding capacity. Circular RNAs (circRNAs) are widely expressed in diverse eukaryotic species and are characterized by covalently closed RNA loops through backsplicing events. Increasing evidence has highlighted the critical roles of lncRNAs and circRNAs in plenty of diseases development and progression. Here, we have updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; database to version 2.0 by integrating comprehensive experimentally supported and predicted ncRNA-disease associations curated from manual literatures and other resources. The new developments in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rnanut.net/lncrnadisease/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LncRNADisease&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; v2.0 include (I) over 40-fold ncRNA-disease associations enhancement compare to the previous version; (II) integrating experimentally supported circRNA-disease associations; (III) providing regulatory relationship among ncRNA, mRNA and miRNA; (IV) mapping disease name to the Disease Ontology and Medical Subject Headings (MeSH); (V) providing a confidence score for each ncRNA-disease association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaemons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; hosts online services and databases developed by team of Dr Zhu and Dr Zhang at Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China. And has have integrated LongTarget into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaemons.net/LongMan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LongMan&lt;/a&gt; to implement a seamless pipeline to implement this function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RNA editing is a widespread post-transcriptional mechanism that can make discrete changes to specific nucleotide sequences within a RNA transcripts. RNA editing events can result in missense codon changes in mRNA, modulation of alternative splicing in mRNA, or modification of regulatory RNAs and their binding sites in small noncoding RNA, such as miRNA. Recent studies have developed computational methods to accurately detect more than 2 million A-to-I RNA editing from next-generation sequencing data in different species. However, the vast majority of these RNA sites are in noncoding regions of the genome and have unknown functional relevance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinfo.life.hust.edu.cn/LNCediting/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LNCediting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive resource for the functional prediction of RNA editing in long noncoding RNAs (lncRNAs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gene Transcription Regulation Database (GTRD)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; contains uniformly annotated and processed NGS data related to gene transcription regulation: ChIP-seq, ChIP-exo, DNase-seq, MNase-seq, ATAC-seq and RNA-seq. With the latest release, the database has reached a new level of data integration. All cell types (cell lines and tissues) presented in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; were arranged into a dictionary and linked with different ontologies (BRENDA, Cell Ontology, Uberon, Cellosaurus and Experimental Factor Ontology) and with related experiments in specialized databases on transcription regulation (FANTOM5, ENCODE and GTEx). The updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gtrd.biouml.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GTRD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides an integrated view of transcription regulation through a dedicated web interface with advanced browsing and search capabilities, an integrated genome browser, and table reports by cell types, transcription factors, and genes of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a popular and openly licensed resource to facilitate the integrative and interactive display and analysis of expression, evolution, function of various ncRNAs by deeply mining thousands of high-throughput sequencing data from tissue, cancer and exosome samples. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rna.sysu.edu.cn/deepbase3/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;deepBase&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provided the most comprehensive expression analysis of sRNAs and lncRNAs, the expression patterns of tRFs and snoRNAs from thousands of cancer and normal samples, the correlations between ncRNAs and patients’ survival and the function prediction of ncRNAs in tumor tumorigenesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;cta-group&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/category/databases/&#34;  class=&#34;btn btn-primary px-3 py-3&#34;&gt;&lt;font color=&#39;white&#39;&gt; &amp;lt; Back to Databases &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbmii.github.io/resources/&#34; &gt;
      Alternative to Online Resources &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-angle-right&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
